- [Instructor] Let's explore how to use WebDriver
to click web elements such as buttons and links.
This button doesn't have an ID,
but we can use an XPath query
composed of the element's type and inner text.
To find the element, we'll say: driver.findElement,
and then we'll say By.xpath.
In the XPath, we'll use two forward slashes
to start from the root.
We'll specify the element's type as button,
and we'll say call the text() function on that,
and make sure that it returns "Submit".
Then from here we can say .click().
We can use this same technique to click this link.
The extra spacing here could prove problematic,
but we can take care of that within an XPath selector.
So we'll say driver.findElement By.xpath,
and we'll start with the a element,
and we'll call a function named normalize-space,
and we'll call text() inside of that,
and then we'll set this equal to the text of the link,
which was "Return to index".
From here, we can call .click(),
and that will click the link.
In addition to buttons and links,
there are other types of elements that must be clicked
in order to interact with them.
For example, to choose a color from this color picker,
we'd need to first click the element,
same for the date picker,
and same for these radio buttons as well.
Fortunately, the strategy does not change.
Locate the element with the best locator strategy available,
then use that web element to call the click() method.