- [Instructor] Checkboxes can be selected
or deselected simply by clicking them.
However, you should check the state of a checkbox
before calling the click method
so that you don't inadvertently take the opposite action.
For example, if your goal is to check this checkbox,
but it's already checked, when you call the click method,
it will uncheck the element.
Let's explore how to properly interact with checkboxes
with Web Driver.
Let's first create a web element object
representing the checkbox.
So we'll say
WebElement checkbox =
driver.findElement(By.id("my-check-1")).
Web Driver provides an is selected method
that returns true if the element is selected
and false if not.
Let's call that method.
So we'll say boolean isSelected = checkbox.isSelected().
Now we'll use an if statement
to determine if the checkbox needs to be clicked
in order to meet our objective.
So we'll say, if(!isSelected), meaning the checkbox
is not checked,
then we'll go ahead and click the checkbox to select it.
Now your code will only click the checkbox
if it's not already selected.