- [Speaker] Dropdown menus allow users to select one
or more options from a list
and are typically represented by the select element
that contains one or more option elements to choose from.
Let's explore how to use Web Driver to interact
with select elements.
While Web Driver provides generic methods to interact
with standalone web elements, dropdown menus consist
of both select and option elements.
This unique component requires specialized handling,
and fortunately, we can use Selenium's select class,
which provides methods specifically for interacting
with dropdown menus.
We'd find the select element, just as we would
with any other element, so let's say driver.findeEement,
and we can say By.name,
and the name of that dropdown is my-select,
but then we substantiate a select object with this element.
So let's use our select class and we'll call this dropdown
and we'll say, this equals a new,
and we'll call the select constructor
and pass in this driver.findElement.
Select provides multiple ways
to select an option from the dropdown menu.
The best approach is to select the option by its value
because the value is less likely to change
compared to other approaches.
To do so, we'd say
dropdown.select by value,
and we can put in the value as two,
which will select this option from the dropdown menu.
Another approach is to select the option
by what's displayed on the webpage.
Let's select the option that says three,
which we see here in the dropdown menu.
We'll say dropdown.selectByVisibleText,
and we can put in the text there, which was three.
Selecting by index is another alternative,
though it's less reliable
because the index may change if the order
of options is modified.
I typically use this approach when I don't necessarily care
what I'm selecting,
but I just want to select the first option for example.
The index starts at zero,
which is the label element, so let's choose index one
to select the first real option.
To do so, we say dropdown.selectByIndex
and enter the index.
The select class also provides a couple of methods
to retrieve the selected options from a dropdown.
To get the first option that's selected,
we can say webElement,
and let's call this one selectedOption
and we'll say dropdown.getFirstSelectedOption.
And if we wanted to get all
of the selected options from a multi-select dropdown,
we could do List of WebElements.
We'll call this one selectedOptions,
and we can say dropdown.getAllSelectedOptions.
For multi-select dropdowns.
The select class provides similar methods to allow you
to deselect options.
We can deselect by value by saying dropdown.deselectByValue,
and enter the value there, two for example,
we can also deselect
by visible text by saying dropdown.deselectByVisibleText
and entering the text from the dropdown to one, for example.
And we can also deselect by index,
dropdown.deselectByIndex
and enter the index of the option to deselect,
one for example, note
that these methods will throw an exception
if used on a single select dropdown
because the deselect functionality is not possible
for that type of dropdown.
Instead, you can select an option that represents the empty
or default value.
In this case, it would be open this select menu.
This is often the first option in the dropdown,
typically used as a prompt or a placeholder.
By selecting this option,
you effectively deselect any previously selected options.